Anders Weijnitz

PERSONAL DETAILS

Full name: Lars Anders Weijnitz

Nationality: Swedish (born 1971 in Visby, Gotland, Sweden)

Marital status: Married

Address: Geigenbergerstr. 33, 814 77 MÜNCHEN, GERMANY

Phone: +49 (o) 173 318 18 13 (mob)

E-Mail: anders.weijnitz@gmail.com (Preferred contact)



PROFILE

Swedish Product Manager living in Germany and working internationally. With my feet in technology and my head in product management, I keep the big picture, while also caring about of the details. My job is to bring a competitive product to market, from idea through development, launch and beyond - managing the full software lifecycle.

In the last five years, we have been introducing the principles of lean manufacturing and agile processes in product development. Currently we use a combination of Scrum and Kanban for all development and support. My role during this period has mainly been the role of Product Owner for the system. It has been a big success for us and I am very much a believer in the values of agile practices.

For my next job, I am looking for a position of responsibility where I can leverage my experience, develop as a leader or coach, but also explore and learn in new fields. It could be in roles such as CTO, senior project manager, team leader, product manager or similar.

I work in an truly international environment and am comfortable managing and coordinating work across continents and time zones.

SKILL BASE

- Expertise in digital content management and large-scale online systems for the web
- Expertise in the fields of online and social media, broadcasting and the news publishing industry
- Expertise in product management and product development
- Experienced in leading people and organizing work to meet deadlines
- Experienced in international sales and management level meetings
- Proficient in Scrum and agile development principles and practices
- Experienced in leading project based work, including offshore teams
- · Proven management and leadership skills
- · Strong writing and presentation skills
- *Tech*: Experienced in Java/JEE and modern web development, Internet technologies and protocols *Examples*: Java, JavaScript, HMTL, CSS, Responsive Design, Amazon Elastic Cloud, SaaS, SVN and Git
- Office IT: MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Mac OSX, MS Windows and basic Unix/Linux
- Driving license

LANGUAGES

Swedish - Native language, English - Fluent, German - Conversational level.

PROFESSIONAL CAREER

VP of Product Management, Web CMS at Atex

February 2011 - Present

Managing Web and Tablet Publishing products. Focus on vision, roadmap delivery and key customer relationships. Synthesizing market and technology trends, customer requirements and the vision for the product into a roadmap and development plan. Working with five development teams on three continents.

Global Product Manager, Web Content Management at Atex

June 2009 - February 2011

Part of the global product management group within Atex that works with roadmaps, product planning, and Sales and Marketing support on an international level. Atex has development centers on all continents except for South America.

Product Manager Web CMS at Atex

April 2008 - June 2009

This position was very much an extension of the previous role; Same responsibilities, but with a more pronounced international focus, both in terms of sales support as well as regarding coordination of development efforts.

Product Manager at Polopoly AB

November 2007 - April 2008

As Product Manager, my main responsibility was the mid- to long-term product roadmap. I worked close to the development teams in a very technical role. Another important part of the work was the gathering of requirements and combining them to form a development plan. In this work I coordinated with the CTO, Product Development Manager and Sales and Marketing.

Meeting customers and supporting sales were integral parts of the role.

Product Development Manager at Polopoly AB

May 2003 - November 2007

Manager for the product development team. Planned the day-to-day development activities and managed the team. I also did developer interviews for new recruitment as well as appraisals and salary negotiations.

The position also included technical pre-sales and technical sales and marketing support.

Java consultant and developer at Polopoly AB

March 2000 - May 2003

During this period, I worked as Java developer at Polopoly, with a special responsibility for the editorial web GUI. I also doubled as consultant and designed the early training material and held developer training.

Java consultant and developer at Futurniture

September 1998 - February 2000

Java web development for a number of clients. Mostly short projects (1 – 3 months). The position covered a broad spectrum of web projects, from WCMS enhancements for clients to the design and implementation of a Java Applet for three-dimensional navigation of hierarchical hyperlinked taxonomies.

Java developer at Spectral

June 1997 – December 1997

Development of a Web CMS product targeted at medium sized businesses. My responsibility was to design and implement the authorization system; the part of the software that governs user access to resources in the system, typically group and user permissions to create and edit content.

Java developer at Netentertainment

June 1996 – December 1996

At the time of my employment, Net Entertainment was a startup. My job, together with a colleague, was to create a proof-of-concept for an online casino product, including an SDK for adding new games (Slots, Poker, Black Jack, etc.). Two months were spent on-location in the Caribbean on the islands of St. Kitts and Nevis, working with local developers of a partner company, CaribFX.

EDUCATION

Master degree in Computer Science, KTH Royal Institute of Technology

1993 - 2002

Exam includes degree in human-computer interaction and network programming.

German course, level C1, Goethe Institut, Munich

June, 2012

Four week intensive language training.

Beginning Management [own translation], Course at Mgruppen,

2002

An introductory course that teaches basic management skills. Focused on the Situational Leadership II Model (Hersey-Blanchard Situational Leadership Theory).

Military Conscription as team leader, A7, Visby, Sweden

1991-1992

Received military leadership training as team leader in one of the Swedish artillery battalions.

High school, Säve Gymnasium, Visby, Sweden

1988-1991

High school

INTERESTS AND PHYSICAL RECREATION

Internet technologies and trends, programming, playing guitar, running.